<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc SYSTEM "doc.dtd">
<doc title="OpenShift Dedicated Examples - Crunchy Containers for PostgreSQL">
<description>OpenShift Dedicated Examples - Crunchy Containers for PostgreSQL</description>
<section id="_openshift_dedicated_environment">
<title>OpenShift Dedicated Environment</title>
<p>Here are instructions for running examples on an OpenShift 3.5.5 Dedicated
environment.  For Dedicated, we have built a set of templates
that can be installed into a Dedicated instance to help automate
the creation of Crunchy Container Suite containers.</p>
<p>A defined set of templates are supported for various purposes, including:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
A primary database
</list-item>
<list-item>
A replica database
</list-item>
<list-item>
A full database backup
</list-item>
<list-item>
A full database restore
</list-item>
<list-item>
PGAdmin4
</list-item>
</list>
<p>Each template is described below.</p>
<p>There are some limitations presented by OpenShift 3.5.5 in the way
in which we can scale up the replica databases.  Without support
for dynamic volume provisioning and stateful sets, the replica
databases can be scaled in a more manual way by creating a new
replica database using the provided template.  If you want say
3 replica databases, you would use the template 3 times to create
the 3 replicas.</p>
<p>When OpenShift supports StatefulSets and Dynamic Provisioning, the
replica can be included within a Deployment and/or StatefulSet which
will allow for scaling to be done by manipulating the Replica Count
within the Deployment or StatefulSet.</p>
</section>
<section id="_installation">
<title>Installation</title>
<p>Users can install the templates into their OpenShift environment
using the following commands.</p>
<p>First, add the following lines to your .bashrc file to set
the project paths:</p>
<code-block>export GOPATH=$HOME/cdev
export GOBIN=$GOPATH/bin
export PATH=$PATH:$GOBIN
export CCP_BASEOS=centos7
export CCP_PGVERSION=10
export CCP_PG_FULLVERSION=10.3
export CCP_VERSION=1.8.1
export CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX=crunchydata
export CCP_IMAGE_TAG=$CCP_BASEOS-$CCP_PG_FULLVERSION-$CCP_VERSION
export CCPROOT=$GOPATH/src/github.com/crunchydata/crunchy-containers
export CCP_CLI=kubectl
export PV_PATH=/mnt/nfsfileshare
export LOCAL_IP='hostname --ip-address'
export CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX=crunchydata
export REPLACE_CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX=crunchydata
export TOKEN=yourtokengoeshere
export REG=docker-registry-default.router.default.svc.cluster.local
export REG=172.30.240.45:5000
export REG=registry.crunchydata.openshift.com
export CCP_NAMESPACE=demo</code-block>
<p>You will then need to log out and back in for the changes to your .bashrc
file to take effect.</p>
<p>Next, set up a project directory structure and pull down the project:</p>
<code-block>mkdir $HOME/cdev $HOME/cdev/src $HOME/cdev/pkg $HOME/cdev/bin
cd $GOPATH
sudo yum -y install golang git docker postgresql
go get github.com/tools/godep
cd src/github.com
mkdir crunchydata
cd crunchydata
git clone https://github.com/crunchydata/crunchy-containers
cd crunchy-containers
git checkout 1.8.1
godep restore</code-block>
<p>Finally, you'll change directories to your Dedicated examples repository and create all the templates stored there.</p>
<code-block>cd crunchy-containers/examples/dedicated
./create-all.sh</code-block>
<section id="_example_details">
<title>Example Details</title>
<p>Each example will build a template to be later used by
users when they want to deploy a Crunchy container.</p>
<p>The templates are installed by running the following script
within each example directory:</p>
<code-block>./run.sh</code-block>
<p>When you run the examples, there are variable substitutions taking
place to set the image path and image tags within the OpenShift
templates.  This substitution allows for better support of different
deployments and deployment environments.</p>
<p>You can either use the templates within the OpenShift Web Console
using the <b>Add to Project</b> functionality or use the <b>oc</b> CLI locally
to use the templates to deploy databases.</p>
<p>Within each template directory, there is an <b>example.sh</b> script
that shows how to use the template using the <b>oc</b> CLI.</p>
</section>
<section id="_deploying_images_to_openshift_registry">
<title>Deploying Images to OpenShift Registry</title>
<p>You can deploy the Crunchy built container images to the OpenShift
registry by running the following script:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/dedicated
./push-images.sh</code-block>
<p>The script will create the appropriate image tag and push the image to the
remote registry.</p>
<p>You can verify the existence of the images on your external Dedicated server
through the following commands:</p>
<code-block>oc get is
oc get templates</code-block>
<p><b>If you are a Crunchy enterprise customer, you will need to change the $TOKEN and $REG
values in the push-images.sh script to the ones that correspond to your company's registries
along with your personal access token. The necessary token and server information can be
obtained either through the web console (console.$YOURCOMPANY.openshift.com) or by visiting
your company's API server and requesting a token
(<link url="https://api.$YOURCOMPANY.openshift.com/oath/token/request">https://api.$YOURCOMPANY.openshift.com/oath/token/request</link>).</b></p>
<p>As you use the templates, you can specify the images in your templates using the OpenShift
registry URL as follows for the <b>default</b> OpenShift project:</p>
<code-block>172.30.149.135:5000/default</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_containers_used">
<title>Containers Used</title>
<section id="_crunchy_postgres_container">
<title>crunchy-postgres container</title>
<p>The crunchy-postgres container executes the Postgres database.</p>
<p><b>Packages</b></p>
<p>The container image is built using either the Crunchy Postgres release
or the community version based upon a flag in the Makefile.</p>
<p>The Crunchy Postgres RPMs are available to Crunchy customers only.  The
Crunchy release is meant for customers that require enterprise level
support.</p>
<p>The PGDG community RPMs can be used as well by simply commenting out
the Crunchy yum repo within the Dockerfiles and uncommenting
the PGDG yum repo.</p>
<p><b>setup.sql</b></p>
<p>The <b>setup.sql</b> script is used to define startup SQL commands that are
executed when the database is first created.</p>
<p><b>Environment Variables</b></p>
<list>
<list-item>
PG_MODE - either <b>primary</b>, <b>replica</b> or <b>set</b>, this value determines whether
   the database is set up as a primary or replica instance. In the
   case of <b>set</b>, it means the container is started within a StatefulSet
   in a Kubernetes cluster.
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PRIMARY_USER - the value to use for the user ID created as
   primaryuser.  The <b>primaryuser</b> has super user privileges.
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PRIMARY_PASSWORD - the password for the PG_PRIMARY_USER database user
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_USER - the value to use for the user ID created as a normal user.
   This user is created as part of the setup.sql script upon database
   creation and allows users to predefine an application user.
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PASSWORD - the password for the PG_USER database user that is created
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_DATABASE - a database that is created upon database initialization
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_ROOT_PASSWORD - the postgres user password set up upon database
   initialization
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_LOCALE - if set, the locale you want to create the database with, if
   not set, the default locale is used
</list-item>
<list-item>
SYNC_REPLICA - if set, this value is used to specify the application_name
   of a replica that will be used for a synchronous replication
</list-item>
<list-item>
CHECKSUMS - if set, this value is used to enable the <b>--data-checksums</b>
   option when initdb is executed at initialization, if not set, the
   default is to <b>not</b> enable data checksums
</list-item>
<list-item>
XLOGDIR - if set, initdb will use the specified directory for WAL
</list-item>
<list-item>
ARCHIVE_MODE - if set to <b>on</b>, will enable continuous WAL archiving
   by setting the value within the postgresql.conf file <b>archive_mode</b>
   setting, if not set, the default is <b>off</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
ARCHIVE_TIMEOUT - if set to a number (in seconds) , will specify
   the postgresql.conf <b>archive_timeout</b> setting, if not set, the
   default value of <b>60</b> is used.
</list-item>
<list-item>
PGAUDIT_ANALYZE - if set, will cause the container to also start the
   pgaudit_analyze program in the background
</list-item>
<list-item>
PGDATA_PATH_OVERRIDE - if set, will cause the container to use a /pgdata path
   name of your choosing rather than the hostname of the container which
   is the default. This is useful for a primary in a deployment.
</list-item>
</list>
<p><b>Features</b></p>
<p>The following features are supported by the crunchy-postgres container:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
use of OpenShift secrets
</list-item>
<list-item>
ability to restore from a database backup
</list-item>
<list-item>
use of custom pg_hba.conf and postgresql.conf files
</list-item>
<list-item>
ability to override postgresql.conf configuration parameters
</list-item>
<list-item>
ability to override the default setup.sql script
</list-item>
<list-item>
ability to set the database locale
</list-item>
<list-item>
ability to specify a synchronous replica application_name
</list-item>
<list-item>
ability to specify a recovery using PITR and WAL files, see
   pitr.adoc for a detailed design explanation of how PITR
   is implemented within the container suite
</list-item>
</list>
<p><b>Locale Support</b></p>
<p>Adding locale support to the container is accomplished by
running <i>yum reinstall glibc_common</i> within the container, this
increases the size of the container image and can be removed if you
do not require specific locale support.</p>
<p>You can specify the PG_LOCALE environment variable which is passed to the initdb
command when the initial data files are created, for example:</p>
<code-block>"name": "PG_LOCALE",
"value": "fr_BE.UTF-8"</code-block>
<p>By default, no locale is specified when the initdb command is executed.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_crunchy_postgres_gis">
<title>crunchy-postgres-gis</title>
<p>This container is the same as the crunchy-postgres container except
that it includes the following PostgreSQL extensions:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
postgis
</list-item>
<list-item>
pl/r
</list-item>
</list>
<p>You can test the pl/r extension by running the following commands
for example:</p>
<code-block>create extension plr;
SELECT * FROM plr_environ();
SELECT load_r_typenames();
SELECT * FROM r_typenames();
SELECT plr_array_accum('{23,35}', 42);
CREATE OR REPLACE FUNCTION plr_array (text, text)
RETURNS text[]
AS '$libdir/plr','plr_array'
LANGUAGE 'c' WITH (isstrict);
select plr_array('hello','world');</code-block>
<section id="_crunchy_backup">
<title>crunchy-backup</title>
<p>The crunchy-backup container executes a pg_basebackup against another
database container.  The backup is a full backup using the standard
utility included with postgres, pg_basebackup.</p>
<p><b>Backup Location</b></p>
<p>Backups are stored in a mounted backup volume location, using the
database host name plus <b>-backups</b>  as a sub-directory, then followed by a unique
backup directory based upon a date/timestamp.  It is left to the
user to perform database backup archives in this current version
of the container.  This backup location is referenced when performing
a database restore.</p>
<p><b>Dependencies</b></p>
<p>The container is meant to be using a NFS or similar network file system
to persist database backups.</p>
<p><b>Environment Variables</b></p>
<list>
<list-item>
BACKUP_LABEL - when set, will set the label of the backup, if not
   set the default label used is <b>crunchy-backup</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
BACKUP_HOST - required, this is the database we will be doing the
   backup for
</list-item>
<list-item>
BACKUP_USER - required, this is the database user we will be doing the
   backup with
</list-item>
<list-item>
BACKUP_PASS - required, this is the database password we will be doing the
   backup with
</list-item>
<list-item>
BACKUP_PORT - required, this is the database port we will be doing the
   backup with
</list-item>
</list>
</section>
<section id="_crunchy_pgadmin4">
<title>crunchy-pgadmin4</title>
<p>The crunchy-ppgadmin4 container executes the pgadmin4 web application.</p>
<p>The pgadmin4 project is found at the following location:
<link url="https://www.pgadmin.org/">https://www.pgadmin.org/</link></p>
<p>pgadmin4 provides a web user interface to PostgreSQL databases.  A
sample screenshot is below:</p>
<code-block>|</code-block>
<p><b>Environment Variables</b></p>
<list>
<list-item>
None
</list-item>
</list>
<p><b>Features</b></p>
<p>The following features are supported by the crunchy-pgadmin4 container:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
mount config_local.py and pgadmin4.db to /data volume inside the
container to support customization and store the pgadmin4 database
file
</list-item>
<list-item>
expose port 5050 which is the web server port
</list-item>
<list-item>
a sample pgadmin4 database is provided with an initial administrator
user <b>admin@admin.org</b> and password of <b>password</b>
</list-item>
</list>
<p><b>Restrictions</b></p>
<list>
<list-item>
None
</list-item>
</list>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_dedicated_template_examples">
<title>OpenShift Dedicated Template Examples</title>
<section id="_primary_database_template">
<title>Primary Database Template</title>
<p>Template Name is <b>crunchy-primary</b></p>
<p>Example is found here:</p>
<code-block>examples/dedicated/crunchy-primary</code-block>
<p>This template will create the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
A database container crunchy-postgres as the primary running within a Deployment
</list-item>
<list-item>
A database service for the primary
</list-item>
</list>
<p>This example deploys a primary database configuration
which uses a Persistent Volume Claim for persistence.</p>
<table>
<title label="Table 1. ">Table Template Parameters</title>

<table-header>
<table-column align="left">Parameter</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Description</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Default</table-column>
</table-header>

<table-data>
<table-row>
<table-cell>NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the database service name</table-cell>
<table-cell>example</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PGDATA_PATH_OVERRIDE</table-cell>
<table-cell>should match the name of the NAME parameter in most cases</table-cell>
<table-cell>example</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_PORT</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres port to use</table-cell>
<table-cell>5432</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_USER</table-cell>
<table-cell>the user name to create and use for a primary user</table-cell>
<table-cell>primaryuser</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_PASSWORD</table-cell>
<table-cell>the password to use for the primary user</table-cell>
<table-cell>password</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_USER</table-cell>
<table-cell>the user name to create as a normal user</table-cell>
<table-cell>testuser</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PASSWORD</table-cell>
<table-cell>the password to use for the normal user</table-cell>
<table-cell>password</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_DATABASE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name of the the normal user database which will be created</table-cell>
<table-cell>userdb</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_ROOT_PASSWORD</table-cell>
<table-cell>the password of the postgres user</table-cell>
<table-cell>password</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>SYNC_REPLICA</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name of a sync replica that will be allowed to connect if any</table-cell>
<table-cell></table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_TAG</table-cell>
<table-cell>the image version to use for the container</table-cell>
<table-cell>rhel7-9.6.8-1.8.1</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX</table-cell>
<table-cell>the image prefix to use, typically the image stream prefix of your registry</table-cell>
<table-cell>172.30.149.135:5000/default</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the image name to use, either crunchy-postgres or crunchy-postgres-gis</table-cell>
<table-cell>crunchy-postgres</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name to assign to the PVC created for this database typically NAME-pvc</table-cell>
<table-cell>example-pvc</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_SIZE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the size of the PVC to create</table-cell>
<table-cell>300M</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_ACCESS_MODE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC access mode to use for the created PVC</table-cell>
<table-cell>ReadWriteMany</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>TEMP_BUFFERS</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres temp_buffers configuration setting</table-cell>
<table-cell>9MB</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>MAX_CONNECTIONS</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres max_connections setting</table-cell>
<table-cell>101</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>SHARED_BUFFERS</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres shared_buffers configuration setting</table-cell>
<table-cell>129MB</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>MAX_WAL_SENDERS</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres max_wal_senders configuration setting</table-cell>
<table-cell>7</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>WORK_MEM</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres work-mem configuration setting</table-cell>
<table-cell>5MB</table-cell>
</table-row>
</table-data>
</table>
</section>
<section id="_database_backup_template">
<title>Database Backup Template</title>
<p>Template Name is <b>crunchy-backup</b></p>
<p>Example is found here:</p>
<code-block>examples/dedicated/crunchy-backup</code-block>
<p>This template will create the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
Job which generates a backup container
</list-item>
</list>
<p>This example deploys a Job which results in a Pod
created which will run the <b>crunchy-backup</b> container.  It
will create a backup of a database and store the backup
files in a PVC.</p>
<table>
<title label="Table 2. ">Table Template Parameters</title>

<table-header>
<table-column align="left">Parameter</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Description</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Default</table-column>
</table-header>

<table-data>
<table-row>
<table-cell>JOB_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the job name</table-cell>
<table-cell>backupjob</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>DB_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the service name of the database to backup</table-cell>
<table-cell>primary</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC name to use to store the backup files</table-cell>
<table-cell>backup-pvc</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_SIZE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC size to allocate</table-cell>
<table-cell>500M</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_ACCESS_MODE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC access mode to use in the creation of the PVC</table-cell>
<table-cell>ReadWriteMany</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>BACKUP_USER</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres user to use when performing the backup</table-cell>
<table-cell>primary</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>BACKUP_PASS</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres user password to use when performing the backup</table-cell>
<table-cell>primary</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image prefix to use, typically the registry IP address and namespace</table-cell>
<table-cell>172.30.149.135:5000/default</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_TAG</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image version to use</table-cell>
<table-cell>rhel7-9.6.8-1.8.1</table-cell>
</table-row>
</table-data>
</table>
</section>
<section id="_restore_database_template">
<title>Restore Database Template</title>
<p>Template Name is <b>crunchy-restore</b></p>
<p>Example is found here:</p>
<code-block>examples/dedicated/crunchy-restore</code-block>
<p>This template will create the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
A database container named crunchy-postgres
</list-item>
<list-item>
A database service
</list-item>
</list>
<p>This example performs a database restore using a backup archive
found in a PVC.</p>
<table>
<title label="Table 3. ">Table Template Parameters</title>

<table-header>
<table-column align="left">Parameter</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Description</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Default</table-column>
</table-header>

<table-data>
<table-row>
<table-cell>NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the job name</table-cell>
<table-cell>restoredb</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_PORT</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres port to use</table-cell>
<table-cell>5432</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_USER</table-cell>
<table-cell>the user name to create and use for a primary user</table-cell>
<table-cell>primaryuser</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_PASSWORD</table-cell>
<table-cell>the password to use for the primary user</table-cell>
<table-cell>password</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_USER</table-cell>
<table-cell>the user name to create as a normal user</table-cell>
<table-cell>testuser</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PASSWORD</table-cell>
<table-cell>the password to use for the normal user</table-cell>
<table-cell>password</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_DATABASE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name of the the normal user database which will be created</table-cell>
<table-cell>userdb</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_ROOT_PASSWORD</table-cell>
<table-cell>the password of the postgres user</table-cell>
<table-cell>password</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PGDATA_PATH_OVERRIDE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name to overide the pgdata path with typically the NAME value</table-cell>
<table-cell>restoredb</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC name to use when creating the new PVC typically NAME-pvc</table-cell>
<table-cell>restoredb-pvc</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_SIZE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC size to allocate</table-cell>
<table-cell>500M</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_ACCESS_MODE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC access mode to use in the creation of the PVC</table-cell>
<table-cell>ReadWriteMany</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>BACKUP_PATH</table-cell>
<table-cell>the backup archive path to restore from</table-cell>
<table-cell>primary7-backups/2017-04-04-09-42-53</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>BACKUP_PVC</table-cell>
<table-cell>the backup archive PVC to restore from</table-cell>
<table-cell>backup-pvc</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image prefix to use, typically the registy IP address and namespace</table-cell>
<table-cell>172.30.149.135:5000/default</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image name to use, must match the image name used in the original db</table-cell>
<table-cell>crunchy-postgres</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_TAG</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image version to use</table-cell>
<table-cell>rhel7-9.6.8-1.8.1</table-cell>
</table-row>
</table-data>
</table>
</section>
<section id="_replica_database_template">
<title>Replica Database Template</title>
<p>Template names is <b>crunchy-replica</b></p>
<p>Example is found here:</p>
<code-block>examples/dedicated/crunchy-replica</code-block>
<p>These templates create the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
replica database container crunchy-postgres using Persistent Volume Claim
</list-item>
<list-item>
service for replica
</list-item>
</list>
<table>
<title label="Table 4. ">Table Template Parameters</title>

<table-header>
<table-column align="left">Parameter</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Description</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Default</table-column>
</table-header>

<table-data>
<table-row>
<table-cell>SERVICE_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name to use for the database service</table-cell>
<table-cell>replica</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_HOST</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres primary service name the replica will connect to</table-cell>
<table-cell>primary</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_PORT</table-cell>
<table-cell>the postgres port to use</table-cell>
<table-cell>5432</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_USER</table-cell>
<table-cell>the user name to create and use for a primary user</table-cell>
<table-cell>primaryuser</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PG_PRIMARY_PASSWORD</table-cell>
<table-cell>the password to use for the primary user</table-cell>
<table-cell>password</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC name to use when creating the new PVC typically NAME-pvc</table-cell>
<table-cell>restoredb-pvc</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_SIZE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC size to allocate</table-cell>
<table-cell>500M</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_ACCESS_MODE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC access mode to use in the creation of the PVC</table-cell>
<table-cell>ReadWriteMany</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image prefix to use, typically the registy IP address and namespace</table-cell>
<table-cell>172.30.149.135:5000/default</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image name to use, must match the image name used in the original db</table-cell>
<table-cell>crunchy-postgres</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_TAG</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image version to use</table-cell>
<table-cell>rhel7-9.6.8-1.8.1</table-cell>
</table-row>
</table-data>
</table>
</section>
<section id="_pgadmin4_web_user_interface_template">
<title>pgadmin4 Web User Interface Template</title>
<p>Template Name is <b>crunchy-pgadmin4</b></p>
<p>Example is found here:</p>
<code-block>examples/dedicated/crunchy-pgadmin4</code-block>
<p>This template will create the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
PVC for the pgadmin4 configuration files and database
</list-item>
<list-item>
pod containing the crunchy-pgadmin4 container
</list-item>
<list-item>
service for the pgadmin4 container
</list-item>
</list>
<table>
<title label="Table 5. ">Table Template Parameters</title>

<table-header>
<table-column align="left">Parameter</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Description</table-column>
<table-column align="left">Default</table-column>
</table-header>

<table-data>
<table-row>
<table-cell>NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name to use for the pgadmin4 service</table-cell>
<table-cell>pgadmin4</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_NAME</table-cell>
<table-cell>the name to assign to the PVC created for this pgadmin4 typically NAME-pvc</table-cell>
<table-cell>pgadmin4-pvc</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_SIZE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the size of the PVC to create</table-cell>
<table-cell>300M</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>PVC_ACCESS_MODE</table-cell>
<table-cell>the PVC access mode to use for the created PVC</table-cell>
<table-cell>ReadWriteMany</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_PREFIX</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image prefix to use, typically the registy IP address and namespace</table-cell>
<table-cell>172.30.149.135:5000/default</table-cell>
</table-row>
<table-row>
<table-cell>CCP_IMAGE_TAG</table-cell>
<table-cell>the container image version to use</table-cell>
<table-cell>rhel7-9.6.8-1.8.1</table-cell>
</table-row>
</table-data>
</table>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_legal_notices">
<title>Legal Notices</title>
<p>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 Crunchy Data Solutions, Inc.</p>
<p>CRUNCHY DATA SOLUTIONS, INC. PROVIDES THIS GUIDE <quote>AS IS</quote> WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF NON INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.</p>
<p>Crunchy, Crunchy Data Solutions, Inc. and the Crunchy Hippo Logo are trademarks of Crunchy Data Solutions, Inc.</p>
</section>
</doc>
